Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Senior Prize Essays
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of History, Yale University, senior prize essays
1991-2018
RU 170
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
18.25
43 boxes
412.27
The materials consist of senior prize essays transferred by the Department of History since 1991. A few essays by non-seniors are also included.
Yale University. Department of History
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Department of History, 1991-2018.
Related Material
Yale Student Papers Collection (RU 331).
Existence and Location of Originals
Senior prize essays transferred prior to 1991 are classed in the Yale Student Papers Collection (RU 331).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of senior prize essays transferred by the Department of History since 1991. A few essays by non-seniors are also included.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
History -- Study and teaching; Essays; Yale University -- Awards; Yale University -- Students
- History senior essay prize winners, 1990-2003; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The essays are arranged chronologically by academic year and alphabetically by author therein. Non-senior essay writers are indicated by a class year in parentheses after their name. The name of the prize, if known, is listed in italics.
  - 1990-1991
    - Bosworth, Hillary. "Protecting the Female Line: Courtship and Class Descent in the American City, 1830-1870" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Breaks, Katherine. "The Ladies of the OSS: The Apron Strings of Intelligence in World War II" (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Brown, Josiah. "Changing with the Times: Food for Peace as an Instrument, and a Reflection, of Policy" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fuentes, Robert M. "The Modern Babylon: The Development of London Municipal Government, 1848-1888" (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Jacobs, Greg. "What We Must Do Well: Implementation vs. Desegregation in the Columbus Public School System, 1973-1985" (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Pollak, Harrison. "European Naturalists and the Emerging Idea of the Amazon, 1743-1866" (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Woo, Ilyon. ""Picture Bride" Nineteenth Century European/Contemporary Asian Cultural Criticism" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1991-1992
    - Gordon, Benjamin (1995). "United States Policy in Palestine, May 14, 1948: A Study of the Factors Influencing the Issue of Recognition of the United States" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Harrington, David. "The Great Mother, the Hampton Institute and its Indian Students: A Portrait of Assimilation" Edwin D. Small Prize (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Power, Samantha."Public Diplomacy for the Contras: Ronald Reagan"s "New Art Form"" Katherine K. Walker Prize (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Ruxin, Joshua."Magic Bullet: The History of Oral Rehydration Therapy" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Ryan, Antony. "The Scientific Marxist: Rudolf Hilferding's Theory and Practice" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Siegel, Andrew (1993). "Product of the Union: British Public Opinion, the American Civil War, and Reform" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Smith, Dylan. "Worthless Freedom?: The Confederate Congress Debates Slave Enlistment" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - West, Stuart C. "Journalists and the Marshall Plan: Three Case Studies of the Press and its Role in U.S. Foreign Policy Making" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1992-1993
    - Cho, Erin K. "Portrait of an Empress" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Gates, Lorraine. ""An Organization of Impeccably Respectable Southern White Women": The Women's Emergency Committee and the Little Rock School Crisis" Katherine K. Walker Prize (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Kaduboski, Mark S. ""Into theFurnace"... Italy's Entrance into the Great War" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Keohane, Nathaniel O. "The Rational Behavior of Antebellum Cotton Growers: The Lack of Response to Agricultural Reform in South Carolina" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Klein, Matthew. "The Development of Scattered Site Housing in New Haven: A Process of Conflict" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - McDow, Thomas F. "Indlela Yona AmaZulu Ahamba ngayo Empini KwamaNgisi namaBhunu, ngo 1899-1902: The Role of the Zulu in the Anglo-Boer War, 1899-1902" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Miles, Anthony R. "Purgatory of Color: The Legal vs. the Social Status of Free Blacks in Antebellum Fairfax County, Virginia" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Papenfuse, Eric Robert. "The Evils of Necessity: Robert Goodloe Harper and the Moral Dilemma of Slavery" Katherine K. Walker Prize (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Pearsall, Sarah M. S. "Past All Shame and Womanhood: Witchcraft and Monstrous Births in Early Modern England" Winifred Sturly Prize (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1993-1994
    - Cherney, Elena. "Raymond-Raoul Lambert: Within the System" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Clippinger, Kathryn A. ""Dutiful 'til Death": The Life of Ann Dudley Winthrop (1684-1776)" Katherine K. Walker Prize (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Eustace, Nicole. "Forefathers: An Exploration of Fatherhood in Colonial New England" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Freehling, Alison. "All in the Family? The Master-Slave Relationship in Colonial Connecticut" Katherine K. Walker Prize (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Printy, Michael O"Neill. "Kings, Monks, and Cows: Perspectives on Cattle Raidings in Medieval Ireland" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Rhee, Jennie H. "In Black and White: 20th Century Race Relations, Law and Chinese in the Mississippi Delta" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - 1994-1995
    - Boggs, Coleen M. "British Sporting Culture and the Quest for a National Identity" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Courey, Jeffrey P. "Conscience of the Nation: William Ellery Channing and the Potential for Moderate Anti-Slavery" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Ezer, Deborah J. (1996). "The Eye of a Storm: The Lincoln Memorial and the Vietnam Era" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Gentin, Danielle A. "Accusation at the Riverbank: The Blois Blood Libel of 1171" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Hahn, Sarah C. "Selling the Negro: The Creation of a National Black Consumer Market,1920-1960" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Smolenski, John. "The Influence of Quaker Theology and Meeting Structure on Pennsylvania Politics, 1682-1764" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 1995-1996
    - Amdemariam, Hara H. ""Chiefs" British Public Schools and Colonial Service Recruitment, 1880-1930" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Civin, Joshua. "The Cost of Joining: The Maryland Abolition Society, its Successors, and the Meaning of Voluntary Association 1789-1819" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Hayek, Andrew. "The Early Walter Lippmann and the Question of Elites in Democracy" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Miranda, Diego E. (1997). "The Sultanistic Regime and Democratization: The Case of Nicaragua" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Shugerman, Jed. "Slavery's Manifest Destiny: The Louisiana Purchase and the Reopening of South Carolina's Slave Trade in 1803" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Zelljadt, Katherine. "Finding a Place: Women Doctors and Civil Society in Russia, 1870-1905" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - 1996-1997
    - Anderson, Michelle. "The American Press and Emerging Environmentalism, 1962-69" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Davis, Jonathan. "Making Democracy Safe For the Indians: TheRhetoric of American Indian Patriotism and Military Service in the First World War" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Dean, Edward. "Robert Morrison and George Thomas Staunton: British Efforts to Break Through the Language Barrier in China Between the Macartney and Amherst Embassies" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Hayden, Liam. "Myth and Reality: Bihac and the War in Bosnia" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Jakes, Susan Johanna. "'The Last Ditchers' Club: American Journalists, Military Observers, and the Spirit of Hankou, 1938" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Nelson, Justin. "Drafting Lyndon Johnson: The President's Secret Role in the 1968 Democratic Convention" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - 1997-1998
    - Best, Charles. "A Man Must Take It As It Comes: A Prospector's Life in 1860s California" Howard R. Lamar Prize (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Boger, Gretchen Elisabeth. "Pushing the Envelope: The Civil Rights Activism of Pauli Murray" Edwin W. Small Prize and Steer Prize in Women"s Studies (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Brundige, Elizabeth Walker. "To Have a Fair Election: Women's Suffrage in Republican New Jersey" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Carp, Benjamin. "Fire of Liberty: Fire Fighters and the American Revolution" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Cohen, Harlan Grant. "Jordan and The Baghdad Pact: The Failure of British Middle East Policy, 1955-1956" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Deutsch, Rebecca. "Redefining Virtue: The Radical Revolutionary Experience of Philadelphia Women" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Douglas, Vanja. "The Church Socialist League" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Finn, Katherine (Kelly) B. "The Supreme Court's Smith Act Decisions: A Case Study in Judicial Self-Correction" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Franklin, Cary. "Feminism Reflected "in the Mirror of Thought": Dora Marsden, Rebecca West, and Feminist Modernism" Winifred Sturley Prize and Steer Prize in Women"s Studies (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Hanmer Stephen. "Fabricating a Cinematic Legend: Francisco "Pancho" Villa and the United States Film Industry During the Mexican Revolution" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Jo, Michael. "James Youngdeer, Princess Redwing, And The Indian Picture in the Silent Era" Howard R. Lamar Prize (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Ko, Albert J. "The Birth and Death of Integralism: Fascist Agitation in 1930's Brazil" Latin American Prize (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Kuo, Joseph Yu. "The End of Tradition: The Dominance and Decline of the Chinese Six Companies of Chinatown, San Francisco, 1950-1979" Henry K. Hayase Prize in Asian American Studies (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Phan, Loan Thai. "The Growth and Change of the Vietnamese Community in Orange County, California" Henry K. Hayase Prize in Asian American Studies (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Rush, Catherine. "The Cunning Art: An Examination of the Nasir Era Through the Life and Works of Naguib Mahfouz" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Shin, Stephen. ""Between the devil and the deep sea": Presbyterian Missionaries in Korea, 1919-1921" East Asian Council Williams Prize (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Smith, Lydia. "Politics, Slavery, and Cherokee Factional Violence, from Removal to War: 1839-1861" McClintock Award for Native American History (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Soskis, Benjamin. "Heroic Exile: The Transatlantic Development of Frederick Douglas, 1845-1847" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Unger, Katherine. "American and Red to the Core: The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Volunteers in the Spanish Civil War" George Watt Memorial Prize (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Van Noy, Cori A. "The Tradition is the Terrain: Local Institutions and the Struggle Over Community Leadership of Chicago's Back of the Yards, 1939-1945" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Wilk, Julia. "A Good Idea Gone Bad: The Problem of Magdalen Asylums in 18th and 19th Century Ireland" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - 1998-1999
    - Abravanel, Karen. "Smoking Mountains: Che Guevara and the Communist Party of Mexico, 1954-1968" Albert Bildner Prize (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Awan, Saira. "A Passage to India: Sir William Jones and British Imperialism in the Eighteenth Century" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Friedman, Michael S. "For the Benefit of the Whole Army...The Development of Union Cartography in the Civil War" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Gold, Emily. "The Wise and Good Physician: The Evolution of James Jackson Putnam's Moral Vision for American Psychoanalysis, 1900-1918" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Goldenberg, Matthew. "Touchdown, Brown: Race, Football and the Desegregation of Birmingham Schools, 1954-1980" Percival W. Clement Prize and the David Potter Prize (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Jones, Kohar. "International Biomedical Ethics Violations?: Research and Control of Schistosomiasis in Senegal by Program ESPOIR: 1990-Present" Andrew D. White Prize--Rest of the World (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Koffey, Quentin George. "Why the Flock Became a Mob: Eva Jane Price and Mary Louise Partridge's Perceptions of Shanxi, China and the Boxer Uprising, 1889-1900" Robert D. Gries Prize and Yale China Prize (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Mascari, David. "Never Command, But Do What You Must: Soviet Aid and Interference in the Spanish Civil War, 1936-1938" Andrew D. White Prize--European (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Pozen, Joanna. "The Most Reluctant Ally: The Franco Regime's Relations with Jews During World War II" Andrew D. White Prize - European (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Rutkow, Lainie. "Their Own Civil War: The Struggle by Homeopathic Physicians in the United States Army to Achieve Medical Pluralism, 1861-1865" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - 1999-2000
    - Alkon, Miriam N. "To Be Free in Thought: The Transformation of Identity Among Jewish Women of Iraq, 1932-1953" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 9, Folder 80)
    - Berrelez, III, Manuel G. "Contesting the Mexican School: Mexican Americans and the Politics of Desegregation in Texas, 1925-1960" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 9, Folder 81)
    - Carbonara, Anne. "The Wedding Culture In the 1950's" Libby Gitlin Prize (Box 9, Folder 82)
    - DeLaurier, Craig. "The Ultimate Enemy: Kennedy, Johnson and the Chinese Nuclear Threat, 1961-1964" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 9, Folder 83)
    - Eastwood, Hugh. "Struggling For Pre-Eminence: Second Empire Paris in the Eyes of Victorian Londoners" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - Greenblatt, Aaron David. "Moldy Figs and Sour Grapes: French Jazz Critics and the Battle over Bebop, from the Liberation to the 1949 Paris Festival de Jazz" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Higonnet, Ethel. "The Sound of Silence: US Press Representation of the Guatemalan Genocide, 1980-1983" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - Hochman, Dalia. "Our History and Our Liberation are Inseparable: Educational Resistance in the Coloured Community of Cape Town, 1976-1986" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - Liberman, Danica. "Hiram Bingham Revealed: The Man Behind the Yale Peruvian Expedition of 1911" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Park, Eunice Y. "The Attitudes and Policies of American Missionaries and Mission Boards Towards the Korean Independence Movement, 1905-1921" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Purdom, Elizabeth. "Henry Hugh Proctor, Prohibition and African American Leadership in Atlanta, 1880-1920" (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - Schenkman, Lucy. "La Nueva Cancion Chilena: The Development of the Chilean New Song Movement From the Early 1900's to 1973" Bildner Prize (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Swan, Andrew. "Commerce Denotes the Pursuits We Explore: The People's "Quasi War" Against France as Experienced by Citizens of Newburyport and Salem, Massachusetts, 1796-1800" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 9, Folder 93)
    - Wies, Katherine. "The US vs the Peoples Republic of China" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - 2000-2001
    - Brainard, Gabrielle. "Party Walls: Understanding Urban ChangeThrough a Block of New Haven Row Houses, 1870-1979" Hegel New Haven History Prize (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - Cheng, Stephen. "Tour of Triumph: The Transcontinental Railway and the Display of Canadian Nationalism, 1871-1989" Canadian History Prize (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Delphin, Renee Caridad. "Rhetoric and Reality: An Examination of the Cuban Race War of 1912" Andrew D. White Prize - Rest of the World (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Edmondson, Elizabeth. "Without Comment of Controversy: The G.I. Bill and Catholic Colleges" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Forman, Edward M. "Maginot Line in the Sky: Scientists and Statesmen in the Safeguard ABM Debate" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 10, Folder 99)
    - Gilpin, Robert Blakelee. "You Can't Win: A Search for Jack Black and the American Hobo" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Greenberg, Kristy. "Operation Just Cause? The Historical Determinants of the U.S. Decision to Invade Panama in 1989" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - Herbstman, Benjamin. "Ecuador and the International Monetary Fund Between 1980-92: A Study of Conditionality and Compliance" Andrew D. White Prize - Rest of the World (Box 10, Folder 102)
    - Levine, Emily J. "Tracking the Female Ego: Dora Marsden and the Intersection of Feminism, Vitalism, and Bergsonian Politics in London, 1907-1919" Andrew D. White Prize - European (Box 10, Folder 103)
    - Lin, Sonia. "Can You Endure to See Three-Fourths of China Go Blind?: Yang-Chu "James" Yen and His Dream of Rural Reconstruction in the Dwindling Years of the Chinese Republic" Williams East Asian Prize (Box 10, Folder 104)
    - Neeland, Leslie. "Black and White Reactions to Sherman: A Comparative Case Study of the Brice Family Plantations in Fairfield County, SC During the Time of Sherman's March" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - Paolitto, Julia. "Defining and Defending Aesthetics: The Photography of Alvin Langdon Coburn and Fin de Siecle Modern Art" David Morris Potter Prize (Box 10, Folder 106)
    - Pollack-Pelzner, Daniel. "All Honor to Jefferson: A Case Study of Abraham Lincoln's Principled Pragmatism" Percival W. Clement Prize (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Pulaski, Alison Holden. "The Manumission of Slaves in Colonial Mexico: Xalapa, Veracruz: 1668-1800" Albert Bildner Prize (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - Ricks, Alice. "Compassion in Camouflage: National Debate as to the Official Overseas Evacuation of British Children During World War II" Winfred Sturley Prize (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - Schochet, John. "The Rise, Fall and Resurrection of BART: San Francisco Bay Area Rapid Transit's Track From Promising Dream to Disappointing Reality to Redemption" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Wu, Sylvia Catherine. "Raymond "Jungle Jim" Kennedy: Yale Iconoclast in a Conservative Age" Yale University Tercentennial Prize (Box 11, Folder 111)
  - 2001-2002
    - Boucai, Michael. "Anita Bryant and the First Crusade: Miami-Dade County's 1977 Referendum on Gay Rights" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - Clazada, Nicolas. "Cuba's Vanishing Revolutionaries: Political Reform and the Leaders Who Broke with the Cuban Revolution, 1952-1961" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Chan, Melissa K. "Arroz y Frijoles: The Story of the Chinese in Cuba, 1847-Present" Albert Bildner Prize (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Croke, David. "Harley-Davidson: Resistance and Recuperation" Libby Gitlin Prize (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Flynn, Heather. "An Impenetrable Secret and a Polished Disguise: Indian Revolts and the Portuguese Inquisition in the Colonial Amazon" Albert Bildner Prize (Box 11, Folder 117)
    - Gaunt, Susan. "Role of the Social Bandit in Missouri's Popular Opinion: Jesse James and John Newman Edwards, 1866-1882" Howard R. Lamar Prize (Box 11, Folder 118)
    - Greene, Hannah. "From Primitivism to Neoclassicism: The Reception of Igor Stravinsky's Dual Styles and the Application of Radical Ideology to Music in Weimar Germany, 1922-1933" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - Ha, Polly. "Elizabethan Puritanism Diverted: Walter Travers and the Presbyterian Response, 1590-1630" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 12, Folder 120)
    - Hornstein, Alison Beth. "Of Bulrush and Whispers: Continuity and Consistency in Crypto-Jewish Custom, 1492-2002" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 12, Folder 121)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Unredacted copy of the essay is restricted. See Box 12a for redacted copy.
    - Kaye, Noah. "Towards a Modern Integration: Systems of Care and the Federal Role in Children"s Mental Health" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 12, Folder 122)
    - Koss, Andrew Noble. "Between This World and the Next: Burke, Coleridge, and Mill on Civil Religion" Winifred Sturley Prize (Box 12, Folder 123)
    - Lanham, Krissa. "An Everlasting Plague: Diplomatic and Missionary Reactions to the Fuzhou Anti-Missionary Riot of 1878" East Asian Council Williams Prize (Box 12, Folder 124)
    - Mutter, Robert W. "La Presse et la Guerre: A New Look at French-Canadian Public Opinion During World War II" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 12, Folder 125)
    - Ralph, William Walton. "The Evolution of American Firebombing Policy Against Japan During the Second World War" John Addison Porter Prize (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Remes, Jacob. "The Conservative Origins of Progressive Social Change: Catholics, Communists, and Cooperatives in Cape Breton" Canadian Studies Prize (Box 12, Folder 127)
    - Richardson, Heather. "California's Gray Legend: Resolving the Contradiction in Foreign Accounts of the Alta California Mission System" Walter McClintock Prize (Box 12, Folder 128)
    - Vo, Nikki Khanh. "Innovation or Imitation: The Tay Son's Effort to Change Society in Late 18th Century Vietnam" Robert D. Gries Prize (Box 12, Folder 129)
    - Weiss, Eli Phillips. "Redeeming Wilkinson: The End of Reconstruction in a Mississippi River County" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - Wilensky, Julie. "The Magical Kunlun and "Devil Slaves": Chinese Perceptions of Dark-skinned People and Africa Before 1500" Andrew D. White Prize (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - 2002-2003
    - An, David L. "The Providence of an Assassination: An Joong-geun and His Search for Patriotism" Andrew D. White Prize - Rest of the World (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Bomba, Nicholas E. "Religious Identity in the Sixteenth-Century Atlantic: "Corso-Pirates" before the Inquisition of New Spain, 1571-1574" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Clopton, Zachary D. "The Barbary States of America: An Analysis of the Barbary Analogy in the American Abolitionist Movement, 1776-1865" Andrew D. White Prize - American (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - Dean, Megan. "From the Front to the Front Page: Describing a Modern Russian Hero through General Skobelev" Andrew D. White Prize - European (Box 13, Folder 136)
    - Feldmanstern, Tova. "A Framework too Pretty for the Picture: Children's Rights in Modern Nicaragua" Max Bildner Prize (Box 13, Folder 137)
    - Floyd, Ryan. "For Want of Rubber: Romania's Affair with Firestone in 1965" Edwin W. Small Prize (Box 13, Folder 138)